

hr@jiholee.me https://jiholee.me Anaheim, CA, 92801 (949) 233-8000



https://www.linkedin.com/in/jiho-lee-dev/

Authorized to work in the United States for any employer: STEM OPT-EAD (11/04/2021)

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer former designer; long experience end-to-end designing and developing front-end and back-end small and large management projects collaborate with 3rd party company, corporate strong relationship with team members. In a rapidly developing modern IT environment, always keep trying to catch and understand the flow of new technology. Regardless of platform, able to quickly hand-on and apply a variety of language, library, and framework.

EXPERIENCE

Jan 2019 - Present

Full Stack Developer • GIT (Hyundai KIA Motor Group)

Irvine California, US

Providing enterprise management service via vehicle diagnostic solution. DevOps inspection management system that integrates with Web Application, Mobile Android, iOS App, Desktop App, API WebService, SOAP, XML, JSON, on .NET framework.

Nov 2010 - Dec 2018

Full Stack Web Developer • Freelancer

Los Angeles California, US

UX/UI design, Blog, CMS, e-Commerce with WooCommerce on WordPress, Magento, Shopify on AWS, Azure. jQuery, Angular, React, Node,js, ASP.NET MVC, .NET Core.

Nov 2008 - Sep 2010

Senior Web Developer • Wewelcom corp.

Anyang-si, Gyeonggi-do, South Korea

e-Commerce solution classic ASP, C#.NET MSSQL, RESTful API, SOAP, XML

Aug 2005 - Nov 2008

Web Developer • SEJONG Telecom (FMR. Onse Telecom)

Seongnam, Gyeonggi-do, South Korea

GIS Web Map Roadmate, Navigation Software, Traffic Road data MRO. IIS, ASP, MSSQL, Oracle, COM+ Sockets, MFC, C#.NET, Window Form, Ajax Mar 2004 - Aug 2005

Assistant Engineer • Onse Telecom

GIS SI business, Signal simulator, UI Design, PDA app, Window Mobile 2003

Jan 2002 - Mar 2004

Designer & Developer • Seil I&C

Gwanak-gu, Seoul, South Korea

Designed and Developed branding franchise websites web application on LAMP

TECHNIQUES

Front-end

HTML5, CSS3, SaaS, Less Bootstrap, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery, TypeScript, Babel, Gulp SPA: Angular, React, Vue

Back-end

PHP, JSP, ASP, C#.NET, Laravel IIS, Apache, Tomcat, nginx, Node.js, Oracle, MSSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Redis NoSQL: MongoDB, MariaDB RESTful API, GraphQL, Prisma

DevOps

Cloud: AWS, Azure, GCP, Heroku CI/CD: GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket JIRA, Confluence, Jenkins, Travis, Netlify, Docker, Kubernetes

CMSs

WordPress, Drupal, Joomla! XE3, WooCommerce, Magento Umbraco, Jekyll, Hugo, GatsbyJS

Extra...

Python, Django, Flask Java, Spring, Spring Boot Ruby on Rails, Go React Native, Ionic, Flutter Agile Scrum Methodology

see more > https://jiholee.me

EDUCATION

Mar 2015 - Sep 2018

Pacific States University

Los Angeles California, US

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems

Jan 2011 - Mar 2015

Santa Monica College

Santa Monica California, US

Associate of Science, Computer Programming

SALES PITCH

As a full-stack developer, more than 10 years' experience in the information technology industry. In the late 1990s, I started HTML with CGI, Perl, and used Flash animation with ActionScript. In the early 2000s, mainly worked on LAMP, Linux, Apache, PHP, MySQL; and after joining a company, based on Microsoft system hands-on with Windows Server, IIS, ASP, C#.NET, MSSQL. In the company, which is Onse Telecom, my last project was about web map service (Kakao map) integrate with the RoadMate navigation system, and my role as a project manager so that work in close collaboration with a team, and highly understand between designers and developers.

Since 2010 moved to the US, during the study in university, to keep working as a freelancer remotely carried out e-commerce related projects to own the end-to-end process. Managing production and communication with multiple clients, using tools Atlassian's Jira, Confluence, Azure DevOps, or Git Book for documentation, and Slack, Discord, Teams, and Jandi for communication. Also, experiences to create wireframes, clickable interactive prototypes, visual design, and high fidelity UX flows and UI designs using industry-standard design tools. To integrate using RESTful APIs with CMS based on WordPress, Joomla!, and Drupal; in NoSQL such as MongoDB and MariaDB for fast and light data processing. As the development of cloud services improves development and operating environment, it is also very interesting to use DevOps through AWS, GCS, and Azure. version controlled with Git, and CI/CD to distribute automatically via helm cart as cloud service composed of Kubernetes load-balancer using Jenkins to build, test, and deploy. In front-end, have switched jQuery to SPA JavaScript and ES6, backbone.js, Angular, and React, refactoring legacy source code to hybrid with Ionic, React Native, and Native Script for mobile apps, still keep trying to adapt modern tech Redux, Hook, Blazor so on as a quick learner.

FREELANCER WORKS

- Reservation Management for ClubSpin (2010)
 - o Club event calendar set a schedule and manage reservation.
- Private Instance Messaging App (2011)
 - o Instant messaging application on JavaScript volatility store message data.
- ASP e-commerce Solution for Comnekr (2012)
 - e-commerce solution for Active Server Page. Only the functions commonly used in the shopping mall solution have been added and the additional functions can be easily installed in a plug-in form. The product manager can change the design easily, and easy to control the supply chain.
- SMS Bulk Messaging App (2014)
 - o Sends SMS in bulk, periodically at a certain time, or automatically sends a specific event occurs.
- E-Commerce Abroad Trading Solution (2014)
 - ASP-based overseas delivery and worldwide shipping solution for e-commerce. The exchange rate
 information is fetched through the API, the price is automatically determined according to the exchange
 rate, and the actual settlement amount can be confirmed by the rate transfer currency.
- Room Control Management for Hobert Residence (2014)
 - Added WooCommerce function to Wordpress base to manage rental payment. A manager could monitor
 the room condition and reservation status. Each employee could log in account and communicate on the
 messaging system, also report procedures. Tenants could pay as subscribers online.
- Landing page for HCA financial company (2015)
 - o HCA static website design for payment with the certified authentication system.
- B2B Wholesale multi-vendor e-commerce (2016)
 - Wholesale B2B marketplace plugin on Wordpress with WooCommerce and Dokan multi-vendor. Build packages for wholesale women's apparel at a package level and offer cheaper features in bulk purchases.
 Several wholesalers and retailers could enter and join as sellers and buyers.
- Lyrics app UX/UI design (2017)
 - o UX/UI design for Lyrics app with responsive web and mobile application.
- ICO landing design (2017)

- Animated SPA website design for the ICO website to show real-time data on display.
- Block-chain company's internal web (2017)
 - Implementing an administrator's internal website functionality for block chaining management.
- Landing page for Chain-sign company (2017)
 - Landing page design for electric contract chain sign system with React.js for flip card counting view.
- Open-market Integration System (2018)
 - The product information is linked with the open market system in real-time, and the order information is linked with the management system. If stocks and prices change, all open markets will be updated at the same time. When the order information is processed by the manager step by step, the order status of the open market is also updated in real-time.

CURRENT ROLE

The GIT (Hyundai KIA Motor Group) providing enterprise management service via vehicle diagnostic solution. DevOps inspection management system that integrates through API. Participated as an active developer and code reviewer to ensure high quality of deliverables. Managing production deployments on multiple occasions. Reducing Deployment effort in test environments by more than 70% by setting up a chain of Azure to perform automated deployments. Ensured to communicate team progress to all stakeholders in terms of status reporting. Providing enterprise management service via a vehicle diagnostic solution. Developing architecture and best practices for easily implementing various business rules into new and existing objects. Design and coding enhancements for an inspection management system that encompasses Engineering, Administration, Expediting, Logistics, Structural Steel, Project Management, and Performance Analysis. Maintaining vehicle diagnostic data loads for a business intelligence system and developed interfaces to send data between server-side audit data and client-side on diagnostic devices such as Mobile Android, iOS Applications with API Web Service, SOAP, XML, JSON. Integrated Web Application, Mobile Android, iOS App, and Desktop windows App.

UX/UI DESIGN

- Understanding of UI/UX best practices and high-quality design.
- Creating visualization flowcharts, diagrams, storyboards, wireframes.
- Experience with developing fully responsive, interactive design.
- Knowledge of cross-platform implementation techniques.
- An advocate of standards designs for accessibility and disability.
- Excellent sense of pixel perfect visual design, colors, patterns, icon, fonts, typography.
- Predicting rapidly changing modern design style trends.
- Dealing with tools Sketch, Adobe CC, Figma, Illustrator, Zeplin, Flinto, Principle, Draw.io, and etc.

DEVELOPMENT

- 10+ years developing web applications with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript ES6.
- 2+ years working with JavaScript frameworks such as Angular or React.
- Experience with a cross-platform and hybrid application with Ionic or React Native.
- Understanding of MVC, MVVM, MVT design pattern.
- Knowledge of Network: DNS, HTTP, SSL, FTP, SMTP, CDN, Firewall, L4 SLB, UPS.
- Experience with OS: Linux, Ubuntu, Centos, RedHat, Windows Server.
- Operating Web Server: Apache, Tomcat, IIS, Nginx, Express.
- Hands-on experience Server-Side Script: PHP, JSP, ASP, C#.NET, Python, Ruby, Go.
- Developing on Framework: Laravel, Symfony, Node.js, ASP.NET MVC, Spring, Django, Rails.
- Designing architecture Database: MS-SQL, Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, MongoDB.
- Cloud Platform experience AWS, Azure, GCP: EC2, ECS, ECR, S3, Lambda.
- Automated testing experience using Puppeteer, Jest, Karma, Mocha, Protractor.
- Building pipeline CI/CD and deploy with Docker container on Kubernetes.